# Arthur Marmin Curriculum Vitae

#### DOCTOR AL RESEARCH

# "Exact optimization of rational models and application to the improvement of chemical processes"

My research interest is in convex optimization and polynomial optimization and their application to signal processing.

- I have worked on the application of Lasserre's hierarchy on several signal processing problems where structures can be leveraged to alleviate the computational complexity.
- I have developed algorithms to solve large-scale SDP problems.
- I have studied the connection between polynomial optimization, tensor decomposition and the moment problem.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

APRIL 2015 — APRIL 2017

# Industrial Technology Research Institute, Taiwan *Research Engineer*

I worked at the System and Architecture Design department:

- I modelled the power consumption and performance of embedded GPU and wrote OpenGL and Vulkan benchmarks.
- I took part in the development of a collaborative software platform for SoC, EDA and IP designers to perform early power and performance analysis and validation. The software is based on SystemC/TLM hardware model and a modified version of Qemu to run Android.
- I implemented image rendering techniques on FPGA to reduce the motion-to-photon delay inside virtual reality devices.

JULY — SEPTEMBER 2012

TeamWork Vietnam, Vietnam *SAP administrator* 

I monitored, administrated and installed SAP

I monitored, administrated and installed SAP systems for Swiss and French customers.

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

SPRING SEMESTER 2020

CentraleSupélec, France *Optimization (2<sup>nd</sup> year)* 

OCTOBER 2017 — JUNE 2020

CentraleSupélec, France

# Reinforcement classes in mathematics

Topics: topology, measure theory, Lebesgue integral, probability, statistics, and partial differential equation.

FALL SEMESTER 2014

National Chiao Tung University, Taiwan Embedded System Design (Graduate class)  117 chemin du murger, 74330 Poisy, France

(+33) 7 69 96 86 40

arthur.marmin@centralesupelec.fr https://www.arthurmarmin.github.io

#### **EDUCATION**

| NOW       | Doctor of Philosophy                             |
|-----------|--|
|           | Centre de Vision Numérique                       |
| İ         | Advisors: Jean-Christophe Pesquet, Marc Castella |
| OCT. 2017 | Université Paris-Saclay, CentraleSupélec         |
| JAN. 2015 | Master of Science                                |
|           | Electrical Engineering and Computer Science      |
| İ         | Advisor: Shiao-Li Tsao                           |
| İ         | Thesis: Design and Implementation of an          |
| į         | Embedded GPU Simulator                           |
| SEP. 2013 | National Chiao Tung University, Taiwan           |
| JAN. 2015 | Engineer Diploma in Telecommunication            |
| SEP. 20II | Télécom SudParis                                 |

#### COMPUTER SKILLS

| COMIT OTER SIRILES |  |  |
|--------------------|--|--|
| PROGRAMMING        | C++, Assembly Languages, Python,<br>LISP   |  |
| HARDWARE DESIGN    | Verilog, VHDL, SystemC, TLM  |  |
| API                | OpenGL, OpenCL, Qt, mlpack,<br>Linux kernel  |  |
| SOFTWARE           | Matlab, GloptiPoly, Tensorlab,<br>Xilinx Vivado Design suite,<br>Git, Doxygen, Emacs |  |

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

| FRENCH   | Mother tongue  |
|----------|--|
| ENGLISH  | Fluent, working operational  |
| MANDARIN | Good working knowledge<br>Used in daily life and working environment |
| GERMAN   | Good working knowledge   |

# **EXTRA INFORMATION**

- I have reviewed articles for IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing.
- I was a visitor at Gdansk University of Technology under the supervision of Anna Jezierska in January 2020.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- A. Marmin, C. H. Lai, H. L. Huang, J. M. Liu, and S. L. Tsao. Design and implementation of an embedded GPU simulator. In *Computer Graphic Workshop*, 2015
- A. Marmin, C. H. Lai, H. Tago, H. L. Huang, and J. M. Lu. Architecture agnostic energy model for GPU-based design. In *Proc. Int. Symp. on VLSI Design, Automation and Test (VLSI-DAT)*, pages 1–4. IEEE, April 2016
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, J.-C. Pesquet, and L. Duval. Signal reconstruction from sub-sampled and nonlinearly distorted observations. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, pages 1970–1974. IEEE, September 2018
- M. Castella, J.-C. Pesquet, and A. Marmin. Rational optimization for nonlinear reconstruction with approximate  $\ell_0$  penalization. *IEEE Trans. Signal Process.*, 67(6):1407–1417, March 2019
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. How to globally solve non-convex optimization problems involving an approximate  $\ell_0$  penalization. In *Proc. Int. Conf. Acoust. Speech Signal Process.*, pages 5601–5605. IEEE, May 2019
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. Sparse signal reconstruction with a sign oracle. In *Proc. Signal Processing with Adaptive Sparse Structured Representations (SPARS) workshop*, July 2019
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. Detecting the rank of a symmetric tensor. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, pages 1–5. IEEE, September 2019
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. A moment-based approach for guaranteed tensor decomposition. In *Proc. Int. Conf. Acoust. Speech Signal Process.*, pages 3927–3931. IEEE, May 2020
- A. Marmin, A. Jezierska, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. Global optimization for recovery of clipped signals corrupted with Poisson-Gaussian noise. *IEEE Signal Process. Lett.*, 27:970–974, May 2020
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. Globally optimizing owing to tensor decomposition. In *Proc. European Signal Processing Conference*, IEEE, September 2020, to appear
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, and J.-C. Pesquet. Robust reconstruction with nonconvex subset constraints: a polynomial optimization approach. In *IEEE Int. Workshop Mach. Learn. Signal Process.*. IEEE, September 2020, to appear
- A. Marmin, M. Castella, J.-C. Pesquet, and L. Duval. Sparse signal reconstruction for nonlinear models via piecewise rational optimization. Signal Process., 179:107835, February 2021